http://enc.uk.net/privacy-notice

Home
About Us
Our story
Who's who?
Who we donate to
What's Happening?
Contact
Data Privacy Notice1.       About usThis Privacy notice is provided by Exeter Network Church (A company limited by guarantee) Charity no 1109486, Company no 05278022.Exeter Network Church and the incumbent of the church, Rev Jon Soper are the data controllers for your data.  In the rest of this Privacy Notice, we use the word ‘we’ to refer to each data controller, as appropriateExeter Network Church is part of the Diocese of Exeter 2.       Personal Data we holdWe hold personal data that you give us.  This information includes some or all of the following:NamesContact information such as Telephone numbers, Addresses and email addressesWhere you provide them, we may hold demographic information such as date of birth, gender, marital status, family composition, dependents, education/work informationFinancial information when you set up a standing order, pay for an event, or provide bank details for the purpose of payroll or reimbursing of expenses such as bank details, payment card numbers, payment/transaction identifiers, policy and claim numbers.As a church we also hold sensitive personal data such as your religious beliefsIf you are an employee or volunteer in addition to above, we may also hold certain categories of sensitive information such as full employment and educational history, references, medical and criminal records.We also hold Information we receive from other sources. Information collected at gatherings and events such as photographs and attendance dataWe may receive information about you from other websites which we use or control, third parties who work closely with us including our church database provider ChurchSuite, MailChimp and finance and payment servicesWhen you visit our website, technical information, including the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, and operating system and platform are collected.  The Church will not collect any personal information about visitors to the website except when they knowingly provide it.3.       How we use your informationWe will use your personal information we collect for the purpose disclosed at the time of collection, or otherwise as set out in this Privacy Notice.  We will not use your personal information for any other purpose without first seeking your consent, unless authorised or required by law.  Generally, we will only use and disclose your personal information as follows:To enable us to meet all legal and statutory obligationsTo establish and maintain your involvement with Exeter Network Church, including informing you of news, events, activities and services we run.To minister to you and provide you with spiritual and pastoral care and to organise and perform ecclesiastical services for you such as baptisms, confirmations, weddings and funeralsTo deliver the Church’s mission to our community, and to carry out any other voluntary or charitable activities for the benefit of the public as provided for in our constitutionTo answer enquiriesTo carry out comprehensive safeguarding procedures in accordance with best safeguarding practice with the aim of ensuring that all children and adults at risk are provided with safe environmentsTo fundraise and promote the interests of the Church and charityTo maintain accurate and up to date records of our employees and volunteersTo maintain our own accounts and recordsTo process donations you makeTo seek your views or commentsTo assist us to improve our services to our members and the community4.       How we store your personal dataWe are committed to holding your personal information securely.  Only Exeter Network Church staff and volunteers that need to see that data can access it.Our database management software is ChurchSuite, you can find out about their commitment to Data Protection and privacy laws here.We may store your data on secure cloud-based software, computers and in paper formAll computers that store any personal data are password protectedAll personal data in paper form are stored in locked offices or filing cabinets 5.       Sharing your personal dataYour personal data will be treated as strictly confidential.  It will only be shared with third parties where it is necessary for the performance of our tasks (for example ChurchSuite or MailChimp) or where you first give us your prior consent. 6.       Our legal basis for processing your dataExplicit consent is obtained to inform you about news, events, activities and services and to add your information to our databaseProcessing is necessary for carrying out legal obligations for example in relation to Gift Aid and other legal requirements.Processing is necessary for the legitimate interests of a not-for profit body with a religious aim provided that the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes) and that personal data is not disclosed outside that body without your consent.  Our legitimate interests involve carrying out the effective and smooth running of church activities and to facilitate the involvement of our members.7.       How long we hold your dataWe will keep some records permanently if we are legally required to do so, we may keep other records for an extended period of time (for more information on retention periods see ‘Keep or Bin: Care of Parish Records’).  In general, we will endeavour to keep data only for as long as we need it.  This means that we may delete data when it is no longer needed.8.       Your rightsUnless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:The right to request a copy of your personal data which we hold about you;The right to request that we correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for us to retain it;The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any timeThe right to request that we provide you with your personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), (where applicable) [Only applies where the processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of a contract with the data subject and in either case the data controller processes the data by automated means].The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable) [Only applies where processing is based on legitimate interests (or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority); direct marketing and processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics]The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office.9.       ContactIf you have any questions about this Privacy Notice or the information we hold about you to exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints, please contact the Exeter Network Church office by email at office@enc.uk.net or by post:Exeter Network Church22 Southernhay WestEXETEREX2 4LYYou can contact the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire SK9 5AF
